<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/Medieval-Castles/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/Medieval-Castles/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-04T00:14:13+02:00</updated><id>/Medieval-Castles/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Medieval Castles</title><subtitle>This is simple project with Jekyll!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Spain Castles!</title><link href="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/Spain-castles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spain Castles!" /><published>2018-11-22T10:44:15+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T10:44:15+02:00</updated><id>/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/Spain-castles</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/Spain-castles.html">&lt;section id=&quot;post-spain&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;spain-castles&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Top 3 of Spain Castles&lt;/h2&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;la-mota&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/Spain Castles/castle_of_la_mota.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;1. Castle of La Mota&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Castle of La Mota or Castillo de La Mota is a medieval fortress, located in the town of Medina del Campo, province of Valladolid, Spain. It is so named because of its location on an elevated hill, a mota (in Spanish), from where it dominates the town and surrounding land. The adjacent town came to be surrounded by an expanding series of walls in subsequent years, of which little remains. The Castle's main feature is the large outer barbican. The interior castle has a trapezoidal plan, with 4 towers and a square yard. It has a large square keep tower, and an inner curtain wall that was used for archers. In olden times, people entered the castle over a drawbridge. This medieval fortress has been reconstructed. At one time it was a well-known prison, housing such people as Hernando Pizarro, a conqueror of Peru, and Cesare Borgia.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;olite&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/Spain Castles/olite_castle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;2. Olite Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A trip to Olite Castle is to experience a different royalty culture in Spain, that of the kingdom of Navarre in the northern part of the country. Also known as the Palacio Real de Olite, the castle was built on first century Roman ruins, though the castle’s construction did not take place until several centuries later. Various monarchs added to it over the years, using a variety of architectural styles, with towers, courtyards and gardens. The castle fell into disrepair, though the Spanish government has been restoring it since 1937. The fortification is both castle and palace, although it was built more like a courtier building to fulfill a military function. Since the 13th-century the Castle of Olite was called as Palace of the King of Navarre. Then the palace was housing the Navarrese court from the 14th until 16th centuries, Since the annexation (integration) of the kingdom of Navarre for the Crown of Castile in 1512 began the decline of the castle and therefore its practically neglect and deterioration. At that time it was an official residence for the Viceroys of Navarre.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;alcazar&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/Spain Castles/alcazar_of_segovia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;3. Alcazar of Segovia&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Alcázar of Segovia, like many fortifications in Spain, started off as Roman fort, but apart from the foundations, little of the original structure remains. A Muslim era fort, which was itself largely replaced by the present structure, was built by the Berber Almoravid dynasty. The first reference to this particular &quot;alcázar&quot; was in 1120, around 32 years after the city of Segovia returned to Christian hands (during the time when King Alfonso VI reconquered lands to the south of the Duero river down to Toledo and beyond). The shape and form of the Alcázar was not known until the reign of King Alfonso VIII (1155–1214), however early documentation mentioned a wooden stockade fence. It can be concluded that prior to Alfonso VIII's reign, the Muslim era structure was no more than a wooden fort built over the old Roman foundations. Alfonso VIII and his wife, Eleanor of England, made this alcázar their principal residence and much work was carried out to erect the beginnings of the stone fortification we see today. In 1474, the Alcázar played a major role in the rise of Queen Isabella I. On 12 December news of the King Henry IV's death in Madrid reached Segovia and Isabella immediately took refuge within the walls of the Alcázar where she received the support of Andres Cabrera and Segovia's council. She was enthroned the next day as Queen of Castile and León. The next major renovation at the Alcázar was conducted by King Philip II after his marriage to Anna of Austria. He added the sharp slate spires to reflect the castles of central Europe. In 1587, architect Francisco de Morar completed the main garden and the School of Honor areas of the castle.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Top 3 of Spain Castles 1. Castle of La Mota The Castle of La Mota or Castillo de La Mota is a medieval fortress, located in the town of Medina del Campo, province of Valladolid, Spain. It is so named because of its location on an elevated hill, a mota (in Spanish), from where it dominates the town and surrounding land. The adjacent town came to be surrounded by an expanding series of walls in subsequent years, of which little remains. The Castle's main feature is the large outer barbican. The interior castle has a trapezoidal plan, with 4 towers and a square yard. It has a large square keep tower, and an inner curtain wall that was used for archers. In olden times, people entered the castle over a drawbridge. This medieval fortress has been reconstructed. At one time it was a well-known prison, housing such people as Hernando Pizarro, a conqueror of Peru, and Cesare Borgia. 2. Olite Castle A trip to Olite Castle is to experience a different royalty culture in Spain, that of the kingdom of Navarre in the northern part of the country. Also known as the Palacio Real de Olite, the castle was built on first century Roman ruins, though the castle’s construction did not take place until several centuries later. Various monarchs added to it over the years, using a variety of architectural styles, with towers, courtyards and gardens. The castle fell into disrepair, though the Spanish government has been restoring it since 1937. The fortification is both castle and palace, although it was built more like a courtier building to fulfill a military function. Since the 13th-century the Castle of Olite was called as Palace of the King of Navarre. Then the palace was housing the Navarrese court from the 14th until 16th centuries, Since the annexation (integration) of the kingdom of Navarre for the Crown of Castile in 1512 began the decline of the castle and therefore its practically neglect and deterioration. At that time it was an official residence for the Viceroys of Navarre. 3. Alcazar of Segovia The Alcázar of Segovia, like many fortifications in Spain, started off as Roman fort, but apart from the foundations, little of the original structure remains. A Muslim era fort, which was itself largely replaced by the present structure, was built by the Berber Almoravid dynasty. The first reference to this particular &quot;alcázar&quot; was in 1120, around 32 years after the city of Segovia returned to Christian hands (during the time when King Alfonso VI reconquered lands to the south of the Duero river down to Toledo and beyond). The shape and form of the Alcázar was not known until the reign of King Alfonso VIII (1155–1214), however early documentation mentioned a wooden stockade fence. It can be concluded that prior to Alfonso VIII's reign, the Muslim era structure was no more than a wooden fort built over the old Roman foundations. Alfonso VIII and his wife, Eleanor of England, made this alcázar their principal residence and much work was carried out to erect the beginnings of the stone fortification we see today. In 1474, the Alcázar played a major role in the rise of Queen Isabella I. On 12 December news of the King Henry IV's death in Madrid reached Segovia and Isabella immediately took refuge within the walls of the Alcázar where she received the support of Andres Cabrera and Segovia's council. She was enthroned the next day as Queen of Castile and León. The next major renovation at the Alcázar was conducted by King Philip II after his marriage to Anna of Austria. He added the sharp slate spires to reflect the castles of central Europe. In 1587, architect Francisco de Morar completed the main garden and the School of Honor areas of the castle.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">France Castles!</title><link href="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/France-castles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="France Castles!" /><published>2018-11-22T10:40:15+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T10:40:15+02:00</updated><id>/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/France-castles</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/France-castles.html">&lt;section id=&quot;post-france&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;france-castles&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Top 3 of France Castles&lt;/h2&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;bamburgh&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/France Castles/montSaintMichel2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;1. Mont Saint-Michel Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;An island some 600 meters off the coast of Normandy, Mont Saint-Michel has been an impregnable fortress since ancient times. The town became the site of an abbey in the 9th century and quickly became a destination for Christian pilgrims, the original European tourists. The abbey’s secure position also encouraged the French monarchy to begin using it as a prison for some of its more troublesome opponents from the 15th century onwards. The site now attracts more than three million tourists a year, both domestic and international, making it one of the most popular attractions outside of Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Now a rocky tidal island, the Mont occupied dry land in prehistoric times. As sea levels rose, erosion reshaped the coastal landscape, and several outcrops of granite emerged in the bay, having resisted the wear and tear of the ocean better than the surrounding rocks. These included Lillemer, the Mont Dol, Tombelaine (the island just to the north), and Mont Tombe, later called Mont Saint-Michel.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;carcassonne&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/France Castles/Carcassonne.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;2. Carcassonne Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The beautiful hilltop town of Carcassonne is more than just a castle. The beautifully preserved medieval town is a historical gem. One of the major towns in the Languedoc region of France, Carcassone played a key role in the Albigensian Crusade in the early thirteenth century. Its tolerant attitude towards religious diversity, and its role as a haven for Cathar heretics ensured that the town was attacked by a crusader army on the orders of the pope. The location of the town remained strategically important, as it is situated in the frontier region between France and Spain. Neglected due to the long-lasting peace between France and Spain countries, the town was restored to its former glory in the 19th-century by Viollet-le-Duc.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In 1853, work began with the west and southwest walls, followed by the towers of the porte Narbonnaise and the principal entrance to the cité. The fortifications were consolidated here and there, but the chief attention was paid to restoring the roofing of the towers and the ramparts, where Viollet-le-Duc ordered the destruction of structures that had encroached against the walls, some of them of considerable age. Viollet-le-Duc left copious notes and drawings on his death in 1879, when his pupil Paul Boeswillwald and, later, the architect Nodet continued the rehabilitation of Carcassonne.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;chenonceau&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/France Castles/Chenonceau.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;3. Chateau de Chenonceau Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;After King Henry II died in 1559, his strong-willed widow and regent Catherine de' Medici forced Diane to exchange it for the Château Chaumont. Queen Catherine then made Chenonceau her own favorite residence, adding a new series of gardens. As Regent of France, Catherine spent a fortune on the château and on spectacular nighttime parties. In 1560, the first ever fireworks display seen in France took place during the celebrations marking the ascension to the throne of Catherine's son Francis II. The grand gallery, which extended along the existing bridge to cross the entire river, was dedicated in 1577. Catherine also added rooms between the chapel and the library on the east side of the corps de logis, as well as a service wing on the west side of the entry courtyard. Catherine considered an even greater expansion of the château, shown in an engraving published by Jacques Androuet du Cerceau in the second (1579) volume of his book Les plus excellents bastiments de France. If this project had been executed, the current château would have been only a small portion of an enormous manor laid out &quot;like pincers around the existing buildings.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Top 3 of France Castles 1. Mont Saint-Michel Castle An island some 600 meters off the coast of Normandy, Mont Saint-Michel has been an impregnable fortress since ancient times. The town became the site of an abbey in the 9th century and quickly became a destination for Christian pilgrims, the original European tourists. The abbey’s secure position also encouraged the French monarchy to begin using it as a prison for some of its more troublesome opponents from the 15th century onwards. The site now attracts more than three million tourists a year, both domestic and international, making it one of the most popular attractions outside of Paris. Now a rocky tidal island, the Mont occupied dry land in prehistoric times. As sea levels rose, erosion reshaped the coastal landscape, and several outcrops of granite emerged in the bay, having resisted the wear and tear of the ocean better than the surrounding rocks. These included Lillemer, the Mont Dol, Tombelaine (the island just to the north), and Mont Tombe, later called Mont Saint-Michel. 2. Carcassonne Castle The beautiful hilltop town of Carcassonne is more than just a castle. The beautifully preserved medieval town is a historical gem. One of the major towns in the Languedoc region of France, Carcassone played a key role in the Albigensian Crusade in the early thirteenth century. Its tolerant attitude towards religious diversity, and its role as a haven for Cathar heretics ensured that the town was attacked by a crusader army on the orders of the pope. The location of the town remained strategically important, as it is situated in the frontier region between France and Spain. Neglected due to the long-lasting peace between France and Spain countries, the town was restored to its former glory in the 19th-century by Viollet-le-Duc. In 1853, work began with the west and southwest walls, followed by the towers of the porte Narbonnaise and the principal entrance to the cité. The fortifications were consolidated here and there, but the chief attention was paid to restoring the roofing of the towers and the ramparts, where Viollet-le-Duc ordered the destruction of structures that had encroached against the walls, some of them of considerable age. Viollet-le-Duc left copious notes and drawings on his death in 1879, when his pupil Paul Boeswillwald and, later, the architect Nodet continued the rehabilitation of Carcassonne. 3. Chateau de Chenonceau Castle After King Henry II died in 1559, his strong-willed widow and regent Catherine de' Medici forced Diane to exchange it for the Château Chaumont. Queen Catherine then made Chenonceau her own favorite residence, adding a new series of gardens. As Regent of France, Catherine spent a fortune on the château and on spectacular nighttime parties. In 1560, the first ever fireworks display seen in France took place during the celebrations marking the ascension to the throne of Catherine's son Francis II. The grand gallery, which extended along the existing bridge to cross the entire river, was dedicated in 1577. Catherine also added rooms between the chapel and the library on the east side of the corps de logis, as well as a service wing on the west side of the entry courtyard. Catherine considered an even greater expansion of the château, shown in an engraving published by Jacques Androuet du Cerceau in the second (1579) volume of his book Les plus excellents bastiments de France. If this project had been executed, the current château would have been only a small portion of an enormous manor laid out &quot;like pincers around the existing buildings.&quot;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Germany Castles!</title><link href="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/Germany-castles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Germany Castles!" /><published>2018-11-22T10:38:15+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T10:38:15+02:00</updated><id>/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/Germany-castles</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/Germany-castles.html">&lt;section id=&quot;post-germany&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;germany-castles&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Top 5 of Germany Castles&lt;/h2&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;neuschwanstein&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/Germany Castles/Neuschwanstein_Castle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;1. Neuschwanstein Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The most photographed building in Germany, Neuschwanstein Castle, is also one of Europe’s most popular tourist destinations. Nestled among the breathtaking beauty of the Bavarian Alps near the town of Fussen, this fairy-tale castle served as the inspiration behind Walt Disney’s Sleeping Beauty Castle. Constructed in the late 1800s, Neuschwanstein was never built for defense purposes as most castles. Instead, this castle was created as a fanciful retreat for Ludwig II of Bavaria. Dazzling chandeliers and beautiful paintings adorn every room in the castle while the third floor is devoted to Ludwig’s fascination of swan scenes from operas by the famous composer Richard Wagner, whom Ludwig deeply admired.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;hohenzollern&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/Germany Castles/hohenzollern_castle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;2. Hohenzollern Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Sitting atop Mount Hohenzollern, the castle had its beginnings in the 11th century. The original castle was destroyed over the centuries with only the chapel remaining. The present castle was built in the mid-19th century by King Frederick William IV of Prussia. Located 50 km (30 miles) south of Stuttgart, the castle is the ancestral home of the Hohenzollern family, from which emperors and kings have emerged. Today the castle is a museum unlike any other. It is filled with treasures including the crown worn by Prussian kings and a uniform worn by Frederick the Great. One of the most visited castles in Germany, it is privately owned.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The first fortress on the mountain was constructed in the early 11th century. Over the years the House of Hohenzollern split several times, but the castle remained in the Swabian branch, the dynastic seniors of the Franconian-Brandenburgian cadet branch that later acquired its own imperial throne. This castle was completely destroyed in 1423 after a ten-month siege by the free imperial cities of Swabia. A larger and sturdier structure was constructed from 1454 to 1461, which served as a refuge for the Catholic Swabian Hohenzollerns, including during the Thirty Years' War. By the end of the 18th century it was thought to have lost its strategic importance and gradually fell into disrepair, leading to the demolition of several dilapidated buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;hohenschwangau&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/Germany Castles/Hohenschwangau-Castle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;3. Hohenschwangau Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The present day Hohenschwangau (&quot;Upper Schwangau&quot;) castle was first mentioned in 1397, though under the name of Schwanstein. Only in the 19th century the names of the two castles have switched. It was built on a hill above lake Alpsee, below the older fortress. Between 1440 and 1521 the Lords had to sell their fief with Imperial immediacy to the Wittelsbach dukes of Bavaria, but continued to occupy the castle as Burgraves. In 1521 they became owners again but had to sell their land in 1535. The purchaser, Johann Paumgartner, a wealthy Augsburg merchant, had the lower castle reconstructed by Italian architect Lucio di Spazzi who already worked on the Hofburg, Innsbruck. He kept the exterior walls and the towers but rebuilt the inner parts until 1547, on a floor plan that still today exists. The older Schwangau fortress however continued to fall into ruins. Paumgartner, after having been elevated to the rank of baron, died in 1549 and his sons sold their new castle to Maximilian I, Elector of Bavaria.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Hohenschwangau was the official summer and hunting residence of Maximilian, his wife Marie of Prussia, and their two sons Ludwig (the later King Ludwig II of Bavaria) and Otto (the later King Otto I of Bavaria). The young princes spent many years of their adolescence here. Queen Marie who loved to hike in the mountains created an alpine garden with plants gathered from all over the alps. The King and the Queen lived in the main building, and the boys in the annex. The Queen's cousin, Frederick William IV of Prussia, had Stolzenfels Castle on the Rhine rebuilt at the same time in the Gothic Revival style.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;schwerin&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/Germany Castles/schwerin-palace-germany-29182-1920x1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;4. Schwerin Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;For centuries the palace was the home of the dukes and grand dukes of Mecklenburg and later Mecklenburg-Schwerin. Today it serves as the residence of the Mecklenburg-Vorpommern state parliament (German: Landtag). Major parts of the current palace were built between 1845 and 1857, as a cooperation of the renowned history architects Gottfried Semper, Friedrich August Stüler, Georg Adolf Demmler and Ernst Friedrich Zwirner. The castle is regarded as one of the most important works of romantic Historicism in Europe and is designated to become a World Heritage Site. It is nicknamed &quot;Neuschwanstein of the North&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In 1167, Henry gave the County of Schwerin to his vassal Gunzelin von Hagen, and the rest of the country around the city was returned to Niklot's son Pribislav, forming a ducal hereditary line that lasted until 1918. In 1358, the County of Schwerin was purchased by the descendants of Niklot, who had been elevated to Dukes of Mecklenburg in 1348. They soon relocated farther inland from Mikelenburg, near the city of Wismar, to Schwerin. During the late Gothic era, the growing prosperity and position of the dukes led to a growing need for a representative castle, and this meant architectural changes to the fortress settlement. The Bishop's House (Bischofshaus) from that period remains in a grave.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In 1837, the ducal residence moved back to Schwerin, but the building was in a relatively bad condition, and the Grand Duke disliked the individual buildings' incongruent origins and architectural styles. Grand Duke Friedrich (1800–1842) instructed his architect Georg Adolph Demmler (1804–1886) to remodel the palace. However a few months later, construction was halted by his successor, Friedrich Franz II (1823–1883), who wanted a complete reconstruction of the historic site. Only some parts of the building dating from the 16th and 17th century were retained.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;lichtenstein&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/Germany Castles/castle-lichtenstein-germany-shutterstock.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;5. Lichtenstein Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Lichtenstein Castle (Schloss Lichtenstein) is a privately owned tourist attraction built in Gothic Revival style and located in the Swabian Jura of southern Germany. It was designed by Carl Alexander Heideloff and has been described as the &quot;fairy tale castle of Württemberg.&quot; It overlooks the Echaz valley near Honau, Reutlingen in the state of Baden-Württemberg. The modern castle was inspired by the novel Lichtenstein (1826) by Wilhelm Hauff and was built in 1840–1842. The ruins of the medieval castle that inspired the novel are a few hundred meters away. The name Lichtenstein translates as &quot;shining stone.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;As a consequence of 19th-century Romanticism, medieval virtues like chivalry became increasingly popular among the elites. Parallel to this, medieval architecture, primarily Gothic style, returned to public attention in Germany with the unfinished Cologne Cathedral, leading to the rise of Gothic Revival architecture. Other notable examples of this romantic infatuation with medieval structures and architecture are the Votive Church of Vienna and Neuschwanstein Castle in Bavaria. This nostalgic longing for the medieval past, spurred on by the works of authors such as Hugh Walpole, Sir Walter Scott, and John Ruskin, meant that architectural had once again turned from the Classical to the Gothic style of architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Top 5 of Germany Castles 1. Neuschwanstein Castle The most photographed building in Germany, Neuschwanstein Castle, is also one of Europe’s most popular tourist destinations. Nestled among the breathtaking beauty of the Bavarian Alps near the town of Fussen, this fairy-tale castle served as the inspiration behind Walt Disney’s Sleeping Beauty Castle. Constructed in the late 1800s, Neuschwanstein was never built for defense purposes as most castles. Instead, this castle was created as a fanciful retreat for Ludwig II of Bavaria. Dazzling chandeliers and beautiful paintings adorn every room in the castle while the third floor is devoted to Ludwig’s fascination of swan scenes from operas by the famous composer Richard Wagner, whom Ludwig deeply admired. 2. Hohenzollern Castle Sitting atop Mount Hohenzollern, the castle had its beginnings in the 11th century. The original castle was destroyed over the centuries with only the chapel remaining. The present castle was built in the mid-19th century by King Frederick William IV of Prussia. Located 50 km (30 miles) south of Stuttgart, the castle is the ancestral home of the Hohenzollern family, from which emperors and kings have emerged. Today the castle is a museum unlike any other. It is filled with treasures including the crown worn by Prussian kings and a uniform worn by Frederick the Great. One of the most visited castles in Germany, it is privately owned. The first fortress on the mountain was constructed in the early 11th century. Over the years the House of Hohenzollern split several times, but the castle remained in the Swabian branch, the dynastic seniors of the Franconian-Brandenburgian cadet branch that later acquired its own imperial throne. This castle was completely destroyed in 1423 after a ten-month siege by the free imperial cities of Swabia. A larger and sturdier structure was constructed from 1454 to 1461, which served as a refuge for the Catholic Swabian Hohenzollerns, including during the Thirty Years' War. By the end of the 18th century it was thought to have lost its strategic importance and gradually fell into disrepair, leading to the demolition of several dilapidated buildings. 3. Hohenschwangau Castle The present day Hohenschwangau (&quot;Upper Schwangau&quot;) castle was first mentioned in 1397, though under the name of Schwanstein. Only in the 19th century the names of the two castles have switched. It was built on a hill above lake Alpsee, below the older fortress. Between 1440 and 1521 the Lords had to sell their fief with Imperial immediacy to the Wittelsbach dukes of Bavaria, but continued to occupy the castle as Burgraves. In 1521 they became owners again but had to sell their land in 1535. The purchaser, Johann Paumgartner, a wealthy Augsburg merchant, had the lower castle reconstructed by Italian architect Lucio di Spazzi who already worked on the Hofburg, Innsbruck. He kept the exterior walls and the towers but rebuilt the inner parts until 1547, on a floor plan that still today exists. The older Schwangau fortress however continued to fall into ruins. Paumgartner, after having been elevated to the rank of baron, died in 1549 and his sons sold their new castle to Maximilian I, Elector of Bavaria. Hohenschwangau was the official summer and hunting residence of Maximilian, his wife Marie of Prussia, and their two sons Ludwig (the later King Ludwig II of Bavaria) and Otto (the later King Otto I of Bavaria). The young princes spent many years of their adolescence here. Queen Marie who loved to hike in the mountains created an alpine garden with plants gathered from all over the alps. The King and the Queen lived in the main building, and the boys in the annex. The Queen's cousin, Frederick William IV of Prussia, had Stolzenfels Castle on the Rhine rebuilt at the same time in the Gothic Revival style. 4. Schwerin Castle For centuries the palace was the home of the dukes and grand dukes of Mecklenburg and later Mecklenburg-Schwerin. Today it serves as the residence of the Mecklenburg-Vorpommern state parliament (German: Landtag). Major parts of the current palace were built between 1845 and 1857, as a cooperation of the renowned history architects Gottfried Semper, Friedrich August Stüler, Georg Adolf Demmler and Ernst Friedrich Zwirner. The castle is regarded as one of the most important works of romantic Historicism in Europe and is designated to become a World Heritage Site. It is nicknamed &quot;Neuschwanstein of the North&quot;. In 1167, Henry gave the County of Schwerin to his vassal Gunzelin von Hagen, and the rest of the country around the city was returned to Niklot's son Pribislav, forming a ducal hereditary line that lasted until 1918. In 1358, the County of Schwerin was purchased by the descendants of Niklot, who had been elevated to Dukes of Mecklenburg in 1348. They soon relocated farther inland from Mikelenburg, near the city of Wismar, to Schwerin. During the late Gothic era, the growing prosperity and position of the dukes led to a growing need for a representative castle, and this meant architectural changes to the fortress settlement. The Bishop's House (Bischofshaus) from that period remains in a grave. In 1837, the ducal residence moved back to Schwerin, but the building was in a relatively bad condition, and the Grand Duke disliked the individual buildings' incongruent origins and architectural styles. Grand Duke Friedrich (1800–1842) instructed his architect Georg Adolph Demmler (1804–1886) to remodel the palace. However a few months later, construction was halted by his successor, Friedrich Franz II (1823–1883), who wanted a complete reconstruction of the historic site. Only some parts of the building dating from the 16th and 17th century were retained. 5. Lichtenstein Castle Lichtenstein Castle (Schloss Lichtenstein) is a privately owned tourist attraction built in Gothic Revival style and located in the Swabian Jura of southern Germany. It was designed by Carl Alexander Heideloff and has been described as the &quot;fairy tale castle of Württemberg.&quot; It overlooks the Echaz valley near Honau, Reutlingen in the state of Baden-Württemberg. The modern castle was inspired by the novel Lichtenstein (1826) by Wilhelm Hauff and was built in 1840–1842. The ruins of the medieval castle that inspired the novel are a few hundred meters away. The name Lichtenstein translates as &quot;shining stone.&quot; As a consequence of 19th-century Romanticism, medieval virtues like chivalry became increasingly popular among the elites. Parallel to this, medieval architecture, primarily Gothic style, returned to public attention in Germany with the unfinished Cologne Cathedral, leading to the rise of Gothic Revival architecture. Other notable examples of this romantic infatuation with medieval structures and architecture are the Votive Church of Vienna and Neuschwanstein Castle in Bavaria. This nostalgic longing for the medieval past, spurred on by the works of authors such as Hugh Walpole, Sir Walter Scott, and John Ruskin, meant that architectural had once again turned from the Classical to the Gothic style of architecture.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">England Castles!</title><link href="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/England-castles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="England Castles!" /><published>2018-11-22T10:08:15+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T10:08:15+02:00</updated><id>/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/England-castles</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/England-castles.html">&lt;section id=&quot;post-england&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;england-castles&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Top 4 of England Castles&lt;/h2&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;bamburgh&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/England Castles/bamburgh_castle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;1. Bamburgh Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Bamburgh Castle is a castle on the northeast coast of England, by the village of Bamburgh in Northumberland. It is a Grade I listed building. The site was originally the location of a Celtic Brittonic fort known as Din Guarie and may have been the capital of the kingdom of Bernicia from its foundation in c. 420 to 547. After passing between the Britons and the Anglo-Saxons three times, the fort came under Anglo-Saxon control in 590. The fort was destroyed by Vikings in 993, and the Normans later built a new castle on the site, which forms the core of the present one. After a revolt in 1095 supported by the castle's owner, it became the property of the English monarch. The castle was briefly retaken by the Britons from his son Hussa during the war of 590 before being relieved later the same year. In c. 600, Hussa's successor Athelfrith passed it on to his wife Bebba, from whom the early name Bebbanburgh was derived. The Vikings destroyed the original fortification in 993.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;warwick&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/England Castles/Warwick-Castle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;2. Warwick Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Warwick Castle is a medieval castle developed from an original built by William the Conqueror in 1068. Warwick is the county town of Warwickshire, England, situated on a bend of the River Avon. The original wooden motte-and-bailey castle was rebuilt in stone in the 12th century. An Anglo-Saxon burh was established on the site in 914; with fortifications instigated by Ethelfleda, daughter of Alfred the Great. The burh she established was one of ten which defended Mercia against the invading Danes.
                Its position allowed it to dominate the Fosse Way, as well as the river valley and the crossing over the River Avon. Though the motte to the south-west of the present castle is now called &quot;Ethelfleda's Mound&quot;, it is in fact part of the later Norman fortifications, and not of Anglo-Saxon origin. After the Norman conquest of England, William the Conqueror established a motte-and-bailey castle at Warwick in 1068 to maintain control of the Midlands as he advanced northwards. During the reign of King Henry II (1154–89), the motte-and-bailey was replaced with a stone keep castle. This new phase took the form of a shell keep with all the buildings constructed against the curtain wall.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;bodiam&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/England Castles/bodiam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;3. Bodiam Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Located to the southeast of London in East Sussex, Bodiam Castle is considered one of the best examples of a Medieval fortress, despite the fact that the 14th century structure was built more for status than for strength. After the conclusion of the 100 Years’ War, Richard II granted veteran soldier and landowner Sir Edward Dalyngigge a license to fortify his home as a measure of protection against French invasion.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Looking like something out of a fairytale, Bodiam has all the attributes that people expect when visiting a Medieval castle, from its soaring towers and battlements to its forbidding portcullis and moat. The interior of the castle lies in ruin, however. It was dismantled during the English Civil War in the 1600s to prevent the castle from being used by the enemy. In 1829, art philanthropist John Fuller purchased the castle for 3,000 guineas to save it from demolition.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;windsor&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/England Castles/windsor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;4. Windsor Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Located about an hour west of London, Windsor Castle is often called the largest and oldest inhabited castle in the world. It is one of the official residences of Queen Elizabeth II who spends many weekends of the year at the castle, using it for both state and private entertaining. Windsor date from the reign of Henry II who came to the throne in 1154. Originally designed to protect Norman dominance around the outskirts of London, Windsor Castle was built as a motte and bailey castle, with three wards surrounding a central mound. Gradually replaced with stone fortifications, the castle withstood a prolonged siege during the First Barons’ War at the start of the 13th century.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;During the Tudor period, Henry VIII and Elizabeth I made increasing use of the castle as a royal court and center for diplomatic entertainment. Today, much of the castle, including the magnificent State Apartments and St Georges Chapel can be visited.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Top 4 of England Castles 1. Bamburgh Castle Bamburgh Castle is a castle on the northeast coast of England, by the village of Bamburgh in Northumberland. It is a Grade I listed building. The site was originally the location of a Celtic Brittonic fort known as Din Guarie and may have been the capital of the kingdom of Bernicia from its foundation in c. 420 to 547. After passing between the Britons and the Anglo-Saxons three times, the fort came under Anglo-Saxon control in 590. The fort was destroyed by Vikings in 993, and the Normans later built a new castle on the site, which forms the core of the present one. After a revolt in 1095 supported by the castle's owner, it became the property of the English monarch. The castle was briefly retaken by the Britons from his son Hussa during the war of 590 before being relieved later the same year. In c. 600, Hussa's successor Athelfrith passed it on to his wife Bebba, from whom the early name Bebbanburgh was derived. The Vikings destroyed the original fortification in 993. 2. Warwick Castle Warwick Castle is a medieval castle developed from an original built by William the Conqueror in 1068. Warwick is the county town of Warwickshire, England, situated on a bend of the River Avon. The original wooden motte-and-bailey castle was rebuilt in stone in the 12th century. An Anglo-Saxon burh was established on the site in 914; with fortifications instigated by Ethelfleda, daughter of Alfred the Great. The burh she established was one of ten which defended Mercia against the invading Danes. Its position allowed it to dominate the Fosse Way, as well as the river valley and the crossing over the River Avon. Though the motte to the south-west of the present castle is now called &quot;Ethelfleda's Mound&quot;, it is in fact part of the later Norman fortifications, and not of Anglo-Saxon origin. After the Norman conquest of England, William the Conqueror established a motte-and-bailey castle at Warwick in 1068 to maintain control of the Midlands as he advanced northwards. During the reign of King Henry II (1154–89), the motte-and-bailey was replaced with a stone keep castle. This new phase took the form of a shell keep with all the buildings constructed against the curtain wall. 3. Bodiam Castle Located to the southeast of London in East Sussex, Bodiam Castle is considered one of the best examples of a Medieval fortress, despite the fact that the 14th century structure was built more for status than for strength. After the conclusion of the 100 Years’ War, Richard II granted veteran soldier and landowner Sir Edward Dalyngigge a license to fortify his home as a measure of protection against French invasion. Looking like something out of a fairytale, Bodiam has all the attributes that people expect when visiting a Medieval castle, from its soaring towers and battlements to its forbidding portcullis and moat. The interior of the castle lies in ruin, however. It was dismantled during the English Civil War in the 1600s to prevent the castle from being used by the enemy. In 1829, art philanthropist John Fuller purchased the castle for 3,000 guineas to save it from demolition. 4. Windsor Castle Located about an hour west of London, Windsor Castle is often called the largest and oldest inhabited castle in the world. It is one of the official residences of Queen Elizabeth II who spends many weekends of the year at the castle, using it for both state and private entertaining. Windsor date from the reign of Henry II who came to the throne in 1154. Originally designed to protect Norman dominance around the outskirts of London, Windsor Castle was built as a motte and bailey castle, with three wards surrounding a central mound. Gradually replaced with stone fortifications, the castle withstood a prolonged siege during the First Barons’ War at the start of the 13th century. During the Tudor period, Henry VIII and Elizabeth I made increasing use of the castle as a royal court and center for diplomatic entertainment. Today, much of the castle, including the magnificent State Apartments and St Georges Chapel can be visited.</summary></entry></feed>