<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/Medieval-Castles/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/Medieval-Castles/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-28T23:17:42+02:00</updated><id>/Medieval-Castles/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Medieval Castles</title><subtitle>This is simple project with Jekyll!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Spain Castles!</title><link href="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/Spain-castles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spain Castles!" /><published>2018-11-22T10:44:15+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T10:44:15+02:00</updated><id>/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/Spain-castles</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/Spain-castles.html">&lt;section id=&quot;post-spain&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;spain-castles&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Top 3 of Spain Castles&lt;/h2&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;la-mota&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/Spain Castles/castle_of_la_mota.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;Castle of La Mota&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Castle of La Mota or Castillo de La Mota is a medieval fortress, located in the town of Medina del Campo, province of Valladolid, Spain. It is so named because of its location on an elevated hill, a mota (in Spanish), from where it dominates the town and surrounding land. The adjacent town came to be surrounded by an expanding series of walls in subsequent years, of which little remains.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Castle's main feature is the large outer barbican. The interior castle has a trapezoidal plan, with 4 towers and a square yard. It has a large square keep tower, and an inner curtain wall that was used for archers.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In olden times, people entered the castle over a drawbridge. This medieval fortress has been reconstructed. At one time it was a well-known prison, housing such people as Hernando Pizarro, a conqueror of Peru, and Cesare Borgia.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;olite&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/Spain Castles/olite_castle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;Olite Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A trip to Olite Castle is to experience a different royalty culture in Spain, that of the kingdom of Navarre in the northern part of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Also known as the Palacio Real de Olite, the castle was built on first century Roman ruins, though the castle’s construction did not take place until several centuries later.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Various monarchs added to it over the years, using a variety of architectural styles, with towers, courtyards and gardens. The castle fell into disrepair, though the Spanish government has been restoring it since 1937.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The fortification is both castle and palace, although it was built more like a courtier building to fulfill a military function. Since the 13th-century the Castle of Olite was called as Palace of the King of Navarre.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Then the palace was housing the Navarrese court from the 14th until 16th centuries, Since the annexation (integration) of the kingdom of Navarre for the Crown of Castile in 1512 began the decline of the castle and therefore its practically neglect and deterioration. At that time it was an official residence for the Viceroys of Navarre.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;alcazar&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/Spain Castles/alcazar_of_segovia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;Alcazar of Segovia&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Alcázar of Segovia, like many fortifications in Spain, started off as Roman fort, but apart from the foundations, little of the original structure remains. A Muslim era fort, which was itself largely replaced by the present structure, was built by the Berber Almoravid dynasty. The first reference to this particular &quot;alcázar&quot; was in 1120, around 32 years after the city of Segovia returned to Christian hands (during the time when King Alfonso VI reconquered lands to the south of the Duero river down to Toledo and beyond).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The shape and form of the Alcázar was not known until the reign of King Alfonso VIII (1155–1214), however early documentation mentioned a wooden stockade fence. It can be concluded that prior to Alfonso VIII's reign, the Muslim era structure was no more than a wooden fort built over the old Roman foundations. Alfonso VIII and his wife, Eleanor of England, made this alcázar their principal residence and much work was carried out to erect the beginnings of the stone fortification we see today.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In 1474, the Alcázar played a major role in the rise of Queen Isabella I. On 12 December news of the King Henry IV's death in Madrid reached Segovia and Isabella immediately took refuge within the walls of the Alcázar where she received the support of Andres Cabrera and Segovia's council. She was enthroned the next day as Queen of Castile and León. The next major renovation at the Alcázar was conducted by King Philip II after his marriage to Anna of Austria. He added the sharp slate spires to reflect the castles of central Europe. In 1587, architect Francisco de Morar completed the main garden and the School of Honor areas of the castle.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Top 3 of Spain Castles Castle of La Mota The Castle of La Mota or Castillo de La Mota is a medieval fortress, located in the town of Medina del Campo, province of Valladolid, Spain. It is so named because of its location on an elevated hill, a mota (in Spanish), from where it dominates the town and surrounding land. The adjacent town came to be surrounded by an expanding series of walls in subsequent years, of which little remains. The Castle's main feature is the large outer barbican. The interior castle has a trapezoidal plan, with 4 towers and a square yard. It has a large square keep tower, and an inner curtain wall that was used for archers. In olden times, people entered the castle over a drawbridge. This medieval fortress has been reconstructed. At one time it was a well-known prison, housing such people as Hernando Pizarro, a conqueror of Peru, and Cesare Borgia. Olite Castle A trip to Olite Castle is to experience a different royalty culture in Spain, that of the kingdom of Navarre in the northern part of the country. Also known as the Palacio Real de Olite, the castle was built on first century Roman ruins, though the castle’s construction did not take place until several centuries later. Various monarchs added to it over the years, using a variety of architectural styles, with towers, courtyards and gardens. The castle fell into disrepair, though the Spanish government has been restoring it since 1937. The fortification is both castle and palace, although it was built more like a courtier building to fulfill a military function. Since the 13th-century the Castle of Olite was called as Palace of the King of Navarre. Then the palace was housing the Navarrese court from the 14th until 16th centuries, Since the annexation (integration) of the kingdom of Navarre for the Crown of Castile in 1512 began the decline of the castle and therefore its practically neglect and deterioration. At that time it was an official residence for the Viceroys of Navarre. Alcazar of Segovia The Alcázar of Segovia, like many fortifications in Spain, started off as Roman fort, but apart from the foundations, little of the original structure remains. A Muslim era fort, which was itself largely replaced by the present structure, was built by the Berber Almoravid dynasty. The first reference to this particular &quot;alcázar&quot; was in 1120, around 32 years after the city of Segovia returned to Christian hands (during the time when King Alfonso VI reconquered lands to the south of the Duero river down to Toledo and beyond). The shape and form of the Alcázar was not known until the reign of King Alfonso VIII (1155–1214), however early documentation mentioned a wooden stockade fence. It can be concluded that prior to Alfonso VIII's reign, the Muslim era structure was no more than a wooden fort built over the old Roman foundations. Alfonso VIII and his wife, Eleanor of England, made this alcázar their principal residence and much work was carried out to erect the beginnings of the stone fortification we see today. In 1474, the Alcázar played a major role in the rise of Queen Isabella I. On 12 December news of the King Henry IV's death in Madrid reached Segovia and Isabella immediately took refuge within the walls of the Alcázar where she received the support of Andres Cabrera and Segovia's council. She was enthroned the next day as Queen of Castile and León. The next major renovation at the Alcázar was conducted by King Philip II after his marriage to Anna of Austria. He added the sharp slate spires to reflect the castles of central Europe. In 1587, architect Francisco de Morar completed the main garden and the School of Honor areas of the castle.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">France Castles!</title><link href="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/France-castles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="France Castles!" /><published>2018-11-22T10:40:15+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T10:40:15+02:00</updated><id>/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/France-castles</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/France-castles.html">&lt;h2&gt;France Castles&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">France Castles</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Germany Castles!</title><link href="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/Germany-castles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Germany Castles!" /><published>2018-11-22T10:38:15+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T10:38:15+02:00</updated><id>/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/Germany-castles</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/Germany-castles.html">&lt;h2&gt;Germany Castles&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Germany Castles</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">England Castles!</title><link href="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/England-castles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="England Castles!" /><published>2018-11-22T10:08:15+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T10:08:15+02:00</updated><id>/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/England-castles</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Medieval-Castles/2018/11/22/England-castles.html">&lt;section id=&quot;post-england&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;england-castles&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Top 4 of England Castles&lt;/h2&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;bamburgh&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/England Castles/bamburgh_castle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;Bamburgh Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Bamburgh Castle is a castle on the northeast coast of England, by the village of Bamburgh in Northumberland. It is a Grade I listed building.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The site was originally the location of a Celtic Brittonic fort known as Din Guarie and may have been the capital of the kingdom of Bernicia from its foundation in c. 420 to 547. After passing between the Britons and the Anglo-Saxons three times, the fort came under Anglo-Saxon control in 590.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The fort was destroyed by Vikings in 993, and the Normans later built a new castle on the site, which forms the core of the present one. After a revolt in 1095 supported by the castle's owner, it became the property of the English monarch.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The castle was briefly retaken by the Britons from his son Hussa during the war of 590 before being relieved later the same year. In c. 600, Hussa's successor Æthelfrith passed it on to his wife Bebba, from whom the early name Bebbanburgh was derived. The Vikings destroyed the original fortification in 993.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;warwick&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/England Castles/Warwick-Castle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;Warwick Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Warwick Castle is a medieval castle developed from an original built by William the Conqueror in 1068. Warwick is the county town of Warwickshire, England, situated on a bend of the River Avon. The original wooden motte-and-bailey castle was rebuilt in stone in the 12th century.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;An Anglo-Saxon burh was established on the site in 914; with fortifications instigated by Ethelfleda, daughter of Alfred the Great. The burh she established was one of ten which defended Mercia against the invading Danes.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Its position allowed it to dominate the Fosse Way, as well as the river valley and the crossing over the River Avon. Though the motte to the south-west of the present castle is now called &quot;Ethelfleda's Mound&quot;, it is in fact part of the later Norman fortifications, and not of Anglo-Saxon origin.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;After the Norman conquest of England, William the Conqueror established a motte-and-bailey castle at Warwick in 1068 to maintain control of the Midlands as he advanced northwards.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;During the reign of King Henry II (1154–89), the motte-and-bailey was replaced with a stone keep castle. This new phase took the form of a shell keep with all the buildings constructed against the curtain wall.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;bodiam&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/England Castles/bodiam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;Bodiam Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Located to the southeast of London in East Sussex, Bodiam Castle is considered one of the best examples of a Medieval fortress, despite the fact that the 14th century structure was built more for status than for strength. After the conclusion of the 100 Years’ War, Richard II granted veteran soldier and landowner Sir Edward Dalyngigge a license to fortify his home as a measure of protection against French invasion.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Looking like something out of a fairytale, Bodiam has all the attributes that people expect when visiting a Medieval castle, from its soaring towers and battlements to its forbidding portcullis and moat. The interior of the castle lies in ruin, however. It was dismantled during the English Civil War in the 1600s to prevent the castle from being used by the enemy. In 1829, art philanthropist John Fuller purchased the castle for 3,000 guineas to save it from demolition.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
        &lt;article class=&quot;windsor&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/Medieval-Castles/assets/England Castles/windsor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;h3&gt;Windsor Castle&lt;/h3&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Located about an hour west of London, Windsor Castle is often called the largest and oldest inhabited castle in the world. It is one of the official residences of Queen Elizabeth II who spends many weekends of the year at the castle, using it for both state and private entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Windsor date from the reign of Henry II who came to the throne in 1154. Originally designed to protect Norman dominance around the outskirts of London, Windsor Castle was built as a motte and bailey castle, with three wards surrounding a central mound. Gradually replaced with stone fortifications, the castle withstood a prolonged siege during the First Barons’ War at the start of the 13th century.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;During the Tudor period, Henry VIII and Elizabeth I made increasing use of the castle as a royal court and center for diplomatic entertainment. Today, much of the castle, including the magnificent State Apartments and St Georges Chapel can be visited.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/article&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Top 4 of England Castles Bamburgh Castle Bamburgh Castle is a castle on the northeast coast of England, by the village of Bamburgh in Northumberland. It is a Grade I listed building. The site was originally the location of a Celtic Brittonic fort known as Din Guarie and may have been the capital of the kingdom of Bernicia from its foundation in c. 420 to 547. After passing between the Britons and the Anglo-Saxons three times, the fort came under Anglo-Saxon control in 590. The fort was destroyed by Vikings in 993, and the Normans later built a new castle on the site, which forms the core of the present one. After a revolt in 1095 supported by the castle's owner, it became the property of the English monarch. The castle was briefly retaken by the Britons from his son Hussa during the war of 590 before being relieved later the same year. In c. 600, Hussa's successor Æthelfrith passed it on to his wife Bebba, from whom the early name Bebbanburgh was derived. The Vikings destroyed the original fortification in 993. Warwick Castle Warwick Castle is a medieval castle developed from an original built by William the Conqueror in 1068. Warwick is the county town of Warwickshire, England, situated on a bend of the River Avon. The original wooden motte-and-bailey castle was rebuilt in stone in the 12th century. An Anglo-Saxon burh was established on the site in 914; with fortifications instigated by Ethelfleda, daughter of Alfred the Great. The burh she established was one of ten which defended Mercia against the invading Danes. Its position allowed it to dominate the Fosse Way, as well as the river valley and the crossing over the River Avon. Though the motte to the south-west of the present castle is now called &quot;Ethelfleda's Mound&quot;, it is in fact part of the later Norman fortifications, and not of Anglo-Saxon origin. After the Norman conquest of England, William the Conqueror established a motte-and-bailey castle at Warwick in 1068 to maintain control of the Midlands as he advanced northwards. During the reign of King Henry II (1154–89), the motte-and-bailey was replaced with a stone keep castle. This new phase took the form of a shell keep with all the buildings constructed against the curtain wall. Bodiam Castle Located to the southeast of London in East Sussex, Bodiam Castle is considered one of the best examples of a Medieval fortress, despite the fact that the 14th century structure was built more for status than for strength. After the conclusion of the 100 Years’ War, Richard II granted veteran soldier and landowner Sir Edward Dalyngigge a license to fortify his home as a measure of protection against French invasion. Looking like something out of a fairytale, Bodiam has all the attributes that people expect when visiting a Medieval castle, from its soaring towers and battlements to its forbidding portcullis and moat. The interior of the castle lies in ruin, however. It was dismantled during the English Civil War in the 1600s to prevent the castle from being used by the enemy. In 1829, art philanthropist John Fuller purchased the castle for 3,000 guineas to save it from demolition. Windsor Castle Located about an hour west of London, Windsor Castle is often called the largest and oldest inhabited castle in the world. It is one of the official residences of Queen Elizabeth II who spends many weekends of the year at the castle, using it for both state and private entertaining. Windsor date from the reign of Henry II who came to the throne in 1154. Originally designed to protect Norman dominance around the outskirts of London, Windsor Castle was built as a motte and bailey castle, with three wards surrounding a central mound. Gradually replaced with stone fortifications, the castle withstood a prolonged siege during the First Barons’ War at the start of the 13th century. During the Tudor period, Henry VIII and Elizabeth I made increasing use of the castle as a royal court and center for diplomatic entertainment. Today, much of the castle, including the magnificent State Apartments and St Georges Chapel can be visited.</summary></entry></feed>